Eric Hendrickson

San Diego, CA 92116 • (619) 505-9276 • eric@erichendrickson.tech github.com/hendrickson02 • linkedin.com/in/hendrickson02

SKILLS

- Programming Languages/Frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Mithril.js, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, XML, Java, C/C++, Bash scripting, Android, Python
- Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Capybara, Mocha
- Experienced with Git, Agile, Mob Programming, BDD/TDD, and Scrum
- Familiar with Windows 10, OS X, and Linux
- Have studied and utilized data structures, algorithms, various design patterns (such as MVC and Prototype Patterns), and JSON/JSON schema
- Conversant in Mandarin Chinese and Spanish

EXPERIENCE

HidIt — Google Chrome Extension (github.com/hendricksono2/HidIt)

November 2016 - present

- Commissioned and paid for by a college student as a study aid
- Uses the jQuery to change the DOM so each word is wrapped by a
- When a user clicks on a word it becomes invisible, making any website an interactive "flash card". If necessary, the user can also hover the mouse over the word to reveal the word, and upon clicking the word cause it to reappear as it was before it was clicked.
- Functionality toggles on and off with click of extension icon

Whelp — Ruby on Rails Web App (https://github.com/hendrickson02/whelp)

January 2017 - February 2017

- Whelp is an app that helps users find dog-friendly events and venues. It marries Yelp's feature of users reviewing venues with Meetups' ability to allow users to find events.
- My main contributions were creating RSVP functionality and with standardizing user roles and abilities using CanCanCan and Rolify and implementing soft delete functionality.
- Site: https://barksandrec.herokuapp.com

Rent-It — *Android App* (github.com/hendrickson02/CSE110W240T10)

January 2016 - March 2016

- App that my team in my Software Engineering course at UCSD created
- Seeks to blend concepts from eBay and Craigslist into a clean, convenient app for the purpose of renting items to others
- Written in Android Studio, used Firebase to manage our database. My role was mostly front end.
- User may create an account, login with username and password, and post and delete listings

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stampr — Intern

February 2017 - March 2017

Interning at a startup that attempts to revolutionize global shipping solutions. I use Mithril to design the front end of various services, including an invoice calculator, and work with JSON schema. I have pushed to the development branch.

Uber and Lyft — Rideshare Driver

April 2016 - present

Active within San Diego County

Yanbian University of Science and Technology, Yanji, China — English Conversation Teacher/Team Leader

August 2011 - July 2013

- Taught English Conversation to Chinese, North Korean, and South Korean students
- Was team leader for my own course, which instructed students with no English language background
- Office responsibility was to manage the computers and software

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy, San Diego — Ruby on Rails Stack Coding Bootcamp

November 2016 - present

Had instruction in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript and completed various projects using these skills

University of California San Diego, San Diego — Extension Studies/Concurrent Enrollment

January 2014 - March 2016

Completed courses in topics such as Discrete Mathematics, Data Structures, Algorithms, Software Engineering, and others

San Diego Mesa College, San Diego — Computer and Information Sciences

August 2013 - December 2013

Took courses in Java and C/C++

University of California San Diego, San Diego — B.A. in Linguistics and B.A. in Chinese Studies

September 2006 - June 2011

- Double major in Linguistics with an emphasis in Cognition and Language Acquisition and interdisciplinary major of Chinese Studies
- Graduated cum laude with a 3.656 GPA and was awarded a Phi Beta Kappa Scholar.

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Because I lived in China for two years and even before that studied its language, history, and culture I am someone who can not only see multiple perspectives but can adapt to them and incorporate them into my own life. I believe that this experience will, when married with my programming skills and problem solving abilities, make me a valuable asset to whomever hires me.